Kevin Dias

Full-Stack Software Engineer

GitHub: https://github.com/SaidNivek

Warwick, RI kevin.vi.dias@gmail.com 401.215.5036

Inspired by the complexities of the web, its design, and its integration to create intuitive, clear, and concise user experiences. Writer-turned-engineer focused on developing excellently communicated web stories for a diverse set of user backgrounds.

Education

General Assembly, June 2022, remote

A.S. Computer Science, May, 2021, Community College of Rhode Island – Warwick, RI **B.A. Literary Arts, 2010,** Brown University – Providence, RI

Skills

Languages: CSS HTML EJS JavaScript JQuery Python React

Frameworks: API Implementation Bootstrap Bulma Django Express Node.js

Databases/Repositories: ERDs GitHub MongoDB PostgreSQL

Potpourri: Excellent communication skills Meeting facilitation Mental Health First Aid

Mentoring experience

Work Experience

General Assembly Fellow, March 2022 - June 2022

- Developed a <u>browser-based card game</u>, employing HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery.
- Created an <u>Instagram-like site</u> utilizing the MEN stack (Mongoose, Express, Node), styled with the Bulma CSS framework, and deployed using Heroku
- Produced a <u>Final Fantasy™ fan site</u> applying the MERN stack (Mongoose, Express, React, Node), complete with user authentication through the application of React Redux
- Constructed a <u>Board Game Geek-inspired site</u>, using Django and Python

Community College of Rhode Island, August 2016 - June 2021

Administrative Assistant to the Dean of Health and Rehabilitative Sciences

- Redesigned 13 health science programs' hard-copy admissions requirements for the web, increasing applications per program by a minimum of 30%
- Coordinated COVID testing event for 800+ students and staff, collaborating with the Department of Health and school leadership, completing task within 30 days

Volunteer Work

Youth-to-Youth Leadership Program, 2002 - Present

- Fostering leadership, teambuilding, communication and problem-solving skills in an active, hands-on, fun, positive group environment with a focus on group facilitation and mentorship
- Staff trainer, educating youth and adults on proper facilitation techniques, how to respond to difficult group dynamics and uncomfortable situations, and to help direct the 4-day event with over 500 individuals in attendance